All right, if you're all ready to go,
we're just going to have a quick little
session for you here. Any media who have
questions, feel free to just go right
ahead. Awesome.
How about um your your past you I mean
you played
you were a wildcat quarterback. How how
does that kind of help you
how did that kind of help you when you
transition to being a full-time tight
end?
Yeah, so I mean, as you know, like I
started playing quarterback in freshman
year of college um
and I just made the switch played uh
quarterback all throughout high school
um but just conceptually knowing the
game um seeing the picture um just kind
of knowing everything just kind of
helped me out when you know you kind of
want to know everybody's
everybody's position at quarterback then
going to tight end knowing just your
position. So, it's kind of slowed it
down for me, I would say.
And I know that like I know Baker uses
the the words quarterback friendly a lot
when when talking about different
targets. So, like your time there being
a quarterback, how can that make you a a
more um quarterback friendly target
yourself? Yeah, I mean that's my main
goal was just to just to pick his brain.
I mean there's so much other respect for
that man seriously just being the QB1 of
the team
but just can't wait to just just earn
earn my earn my trust to him on the on
the role in offense and just be be what
I like to say is a blanket to him just a
friendly blanket just to
cover him up when stuff goes to stuff
goes to crap
just to just to be that guy for him so.
Bower, congratulations. I just wanted to
ask what level of interest did the Bucks
have in you throughout the pre-draft
process?
They had a lot, you know, I I took a
visit took a 30 visit there um
met with the coach. I had I don't
I don't want to say I had a zoom call
but I had a 30 visit so I I knew they
were definitely interested so. And how
did that 30 visit go for you? It was
awesome. I mean just the vibes down
there
my guy Ty that was taking me around
worked at LSU previously so just kind of
know him it just it just fit man it was
awesome.
What are some parts of your game as a
tight end that you're very proud of at
the college level that you think will
translate really well to the NFL level?
I'm just a very versatile player. You
can put me at fullback. You can put me
as a wide tight end. You can put me as
an H. It doesn't really matter. Um
I can do it all.
You ask me to go run down on kickoff and
make a tackle I'm going to do that as
well. You know, all the special teams I
think I'm just a
I'm just a Swiss army knife as they
would say as playing QB
wildcat QB myself my ears so yes sir.
What was that moment like for you? What
were the emotions when you got that call
when you looked down and saw that 813
number?
I don't think there's any tears left in
my my my body. I think they all just got
out like everyone was crying. It was
awesome just to
just kind of you know, I I was
fortunate for one offer out of high
school to play quarterback. Now I'm here
in the NFL tight end so that's just a
testament to how good good God is in my
life so.
Are you in Dothan right now?
>> Yes sir.
Yeah, how is it? How is Dothan up there?
It's awesome. We got a surprise draft
party I had no idea about 6:00 so we'll
go we'll go celebrate that. What what
So, what did you think you were doing
today then? I was just like mom I just
wanted all family like let's just do
family today and so
here we go. We're 6:00 a couple hours
we're going to see her right.
Are you okay handling surprises? I mean
sometimes you have to do that.
Yeah, I mean I know now so it's not
really a surprise but it was good.
Bower, given your frame and the fact
that you benched 20 reps at the NFL
combine, how do you feel about being a
blocker at the next level and kind of
taking on those tough assignments?
Yeah, I mean I wouldn't even say they're
they're tough they're they're
inviting I would say. 20 was not my
number I
I was wanting there's a little low for
me I would say but
I'm just excited to learn and just to
just to be a sponge to the tight end
coach and and the vets in that room
honestly just
as a rookie coming in but I just I'm
just trying to earn the respect from the
teammates to be honest with you right
off the jump and then just
go to work and earn respect by the work
I put in.
What number did you have in mind?
Anything that's available.
And now for the bench press?
Oh oh for the bench press I mean mid-20s
I have no idea. I mean I was just I
thought I was going to get more than 20
but it's all right. Bower, on the
spectrum of tight ends from from pass
catching tight ends to to block first
tight ends do you do you put yourself in
the middle is it something where you're
you're confident with both sides of it?
Say that one more time. On the spectrum
of tight ends from blocking tight ends
to pass catching tight ends do you do
you kind of put yourself in the middle
where you're confident in both sides of
it? Oh, absolutely. I think I'm one of
the most versatile tight ends in the
draft I really do. I just my twitchiness
to top routes and how I create
separation but also the physicality and
twitch right off the ball to
go make a block for whoever it is. One
of the unique things about being like in
the NIL era is that you do see guys you
know, jump around to different schools
and for you how did each destination
that you arrived at how did that shape
the player you are right now?
Yeah, I mean it was all meant to be I
wouldn't trade it for the world.
Everywhere I went just the relationships
that I created helped me help mold me
into the man I am today along with my
heavenly father Jesus but
it was awesome. Each stop I learned a
lot
and began to be groomed as a as a tight
end.
Your mentality on the field especially
when you know you have a run blocking
assignment but what kind of edge and
attitude do you like to play with?
I'm going to be willing to die for the
block right off the bat. I mean there
there is no really uh
really any other any other words to put
it.
I'm going to I'm going to be successful
as a blocker that's all that that's the
nicest way to put it.
Bower, do you happen to know anybody on
the roster or anybody in that tight end
room currently in Tampa?
I do not I do not. I know I mean I'm I'm
familiar with the tight ends they got
but
I I personally don't know anybody. Maybe
catching some passes from Baker Mayfield
though?
That would uh
boomer baby I guess a couple years ago
running that I mean that'd be sick. I'm
excited to meet him.
Bower, right now your given name isn't
Bower right? It is can you can you say
is it a family name? How did you get the
nickname Bower? Uh that's my great
grandparents' last name.
It's actually my middle name I go by
William Bower.
Um
everybody either calls me Bower or just
or just plain old Sharp so that's what
it is.
If you had a message for the Bucks fans
who are watching this right now, what
kind of player what kind of person are
they getting in you?
Yeah, I would just say I'm a go-getter
I'm going to do anything for
for my teammates. I'm I'm in love with
my teammates
seriously I really do. I'm going to I'm
passionate.
I'm a little crazy when I put the helmet
on but I'm going to do anything for for
Bucks nation and everybody around me.
You mentioned you mentioned your faith a
little bit already. Just what role did
that play in this whole journey for you?
Yeah, I mean obviously as a football
player you go through adversity but any
everyone anyone and everyone does that's
kind of my main
vent is is my faith
obviously my family too but that's kind
of what's gotten me through and gotten
me gotten me here today.
Anything else?
I appreciate I appreciate it very much.
Nice meeting you. Thank you.
Appreciate it man.